Kids,as you know, Aunt Robin grew up in Canada.
孩儿们 你们都知道Robin阿姨 是土生土长的加拿大人
That meant sometimes she dressed a little differently.
所以她有时穿得与众不同
Okay,let'do this!
好的 上吧
ThatSometimeshlkedesa le drely.
有时她的说话方式也与众不同
******
Ted 这电费单比魁北克壮汉的胳膊还粗
*************
你们整晚都耗在这 蠢蛋?
She hung out at different bars and enjoyed leisure time a little differently?
她泡与众不同的酒吧 消遣也与众不同
You wao go? You want to go? Come on!
你想走? 你想走? 来吧!
Make fun of the Great White North all you want.
不管你们怎么取笑加拿大
It's the best country in the world.
它都是世界上首屈一指的国家
Social experiment.
来做个社会调查呗
U.S.A.,U.S.A.U.S.A.,U.S.A.,U.S.A...
美国 美国 美国...
Okay,okay. You know what, What ds that even prove,okay?
得了 得了 这能证明啥?
You chant anything, people will join in.
不管你嚷啥 人们都会跟风
Canada,Canada, Cana... Okay,they won't chant anything.
加拿大 加拿大 加拿... 好吧 他们不是啥都跟风
Shrimp fried rice, Shrimp fried rice, Shrimp fried rice, .
虾仁炒饭 虾仁炒饭 虾仁炒饭
Shrimp fried rice, Shrimp friedice..
虾仁炒饭 虾仁炒饭
Shrimp fried rice-- totally.
虾仁炒饭 一绝
Anyway,speaking of food, Marshall,I've got some bad news.
说到吃的 Marshall 有个坏消息
- Just read online, Gazzola's is closing. - No
- 网上看的 Gazzola's要倒闭了 - 不要啊
at's Gazzo.
Gazzola's是啥?
A filthy mecca of spectacular if undercooked pizza located
伊利诺斯州芝加哥Kinzi街316号 那半生不熟的披萨
at 316 Kinzie Street, Chicago,Illinois.
加上蟑螂苍蝇满天飞环境啊
Back in college,Ted and I used to take these crazy road trips from Connecticut all the way to Chicago
大学时 我和Ted常从 康涅狄格州千里迢迢地驾车去芝加哥
just for a Gazzola's pizza.
只是为吃Gazzola's的披萨
**Noap. We'd just jump i the Fiero and drive.
22小时 没地图 我们就一路猛开
We were like Lewis and Clark, if Lewis and Clark peed in empty soda bottles
要是Lewis和Clark也往空瓶里嘘嘘 把哈密瓜敲得"磅磅"响 (美国第一个探险两人组)
and had a bong made out of a cantaloupe.
我们就堪比他们
Man,those Gazzola trips, that's...
哥们 由于Gazzola's之旅 我们才
that's when we really became bros.
我们才成为铁哥们
We ate nothing but jerky.
我们只吃牛肉干
Drank nothing but Tantrum.
只喝Tantrum
Ah,Tantm.
啊 Tantrum
Tantrum was a so drink with thhighest caffeine content legally available over the counter.
Tantrum是一款在柜台合法出售的 含有最高剂量咖啡因的饮料
It was eventually discontinued after an extensive study by the FDA.
最后经过食品药品管理局的全面研究后停产
Oh,man,we went through a whole case of Tantrum one trip.
哥们 我们有次途中干掉一整箱Tantrum
I was color-blind for two weeks after that.
之后我就色盲了2周
I think that's the reason that I pass out when I hear church bells.
我觉得我听到教堂钟声后 会晕掉也和它有关
It's probably a good thing they're closing Gazzola's.
也许关掉Gazzola's也是好事
Those trips were brutal,right?
去那太遭罪了 对不?
The long hours in the car, the motion sickness,the smell.
长时间窝在车里 晕车 那味道
- So what time are we leaving for Gazzola's tomorrow? - I was thinking 9:00,9:30.
- 我们明天啥时候去Gazzola - 我觉得9点9点半的样子
-=http://sfile.ydy.com=- proudly presents
-=伊甸园美剧论坛 http://bbs.sfileydy.com=- 荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=http://sfile.ydy.com=- sync:咔肉肉
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组=- 翻译: 花竹梗 HOLAH 校对: 葱家的小毛毛 时间轴: 咔肉肉
How I Met Your Mother Season05 Episode05
I am ready to hit the road. I got baby wipes.
我要出发啦 我拿了婴儿湿巾
I got a variety of jerky. I got six cans of Tantrum.
好多牛肉干 还有六罐Tantrum
Well,four. One burned through the can,e.
四罐 一罐在我已经喝了  另一罐时自燃了
Tantrum!
I am so psyched!
我充满了力量!
Marshall and I haven't done something,just the two of us,for so long.
在Marshall结婚前 我俩一直亲密无间
Ever since he got married,he's turned from an "I" to a "we."
现在他却从"我"变成"我们"
- What do you mean? - Think about it.
- 啥意思? - 用用脑子
Hey,haven't seen you all week. How you ing?
嘿 一周意见 过得咋样?
We're doing great.
我们很好
Did you watch the Jets game?
看喷气机队比赛了不?
We most certainly did.
我们当然不会错过
How'd things go at the doctor?
医生那咋说?
We no longer have a hemorrhoid problem.
我们痔疮全好啦
You guys wl not believe this. I've been talking to my lawyer all morning.
真是难以置信  我和律师谈了一早上了
You know that guy I had a slight disagreement with at the Hoser Hut?
和我在Hoser酒吧有点小摩擦的家伙
He's filing assault charges.
竟然要告我伤害罪
Come on!
得了吧
I broke his nose with a chair.
我只是拿椅子砸断他鼻子
And now,apparently,I may end up getting deported.
恐怕我要被驱逐出境了
- Oh,my God,that sucks. - Yeah.
- 我的天 糟糕 - 嗯
I'm gonna go do push-ups in the kitchen. Tantrum!
我要去厨房做俯卧撑 Tantrum!
Well,there's only one possible way to avoid getting deported.
只有一个方法能免于被驱逐出境
My lawyer said I could become an American citizen.
我的律师说只要我加入美国籍
Perfect. Problem solved. Welcome aboard.
好极啦 问题搞定 欢迎入籍
Well,it's not that simple. I'm a Canadian. I was born there. My family'there. It's who I.
没那么简单 我是加拿大人 我生在那 长在那 那里是我的根
I know,and it's provided us with a lot of laughs.
我知道 所以才有那么多笑柄
But,Robin, if you want to live here, work here and throw chairs at people here,
但是 Robin 要是你想 在这里工作生活 拿椅子砸人
you have to do this.
你就得入籍
- Well,there's a citizenship test tomorrow. - A cit...
- 明天有移民入籍考试 - 移...
- I'll think about it. - No,no,you have to do it.
- 我会考虑看看的 - 不 不 是必须
I'll help you study. We're gonna stay up all night long.
我帮你复习 我们今晚开通宵
I'm goand nna dren we're . No,seriously.
我们先猛干一番再学习 不 说正经的
We're gonna do some cramming and then we're gonna study.
我们先猛吃一番再学习
No,seriously. We're gonna bone up on...
不 说正经的 我们先死记硬背
- Okay,Barney. - Sorry.
- 好啦 Barney - 不好意思
- It's a rich area. - It is.
- 考试范围很广 - 对的
But you know,it's not going to be easy,this test.
但这考试不简单
It's not like the Canadian citizenship test.
不象加拿大移民入籍考试
How do you know the Canadian test is easy?
你咋知道加拿大考试简单?
It's Canada. Question one: Do you want to be Canadian?
加拿大嘛 第一问:你想成为加拿大人吗?
Question two: Really?
第二问:真的?
Ted! Ted! Check it out!
Ted! Ted! 快来看!
I got black coffee on the left, I got Tantrum on the right!
左边是清咖 右边是Tantrum!
- Do you have a phone bo? - Yes,I do!
- 你有电话本不? - 有!
I don't know why they make phone books anymore. Everything's online,right?
不明白还要电话本干啥 网上应有尽有 对不?
- Tantrum! - Tantrum!
t,et hit the road.
好啦 出发吧
You invited Lily?
你叫上Lily了?
We most certainly did!
我们当然一起去啦
- I don't know if you caught that, but he did the "we" thing. - Yeah,I heard him.
- 你有没发现 他干啥都两人一起 - 嗯 我听到了
Road trip!
开车上路!
So you guys want to talk about bitches?
你们想聊聊骚妞不?
I'm kidding. They're called women.
说笑啦 是女人
All right, next stop: Chicago.
好的 下一站:芝加哥
I have to pee.
我要嘘嘘
- Couldn't you have gone before we left? - I did. I just pee a lot. You'll see.
- 我们走前你咋不尿? - 尿了 我尿多嘛 你会明白的
Don't worry, we'll get out on the road, it'll be just like old times.
别担心 我们半途上解决 一切都跟以前一样
It wasn't.
才不一样呢
?I would walk 500 miles ?
我要走500里
Sugar snap pea? Pea... That reminds me,I have to pee.
甜豌豆吃不? 豆...(pea读音同pee) 唤起了我的尿意
Okay,straight, straight,straight.
好的 直走 直走 直走
Now,wait,a little to the left. We'll pass a state trooper.
慢点 往左 我们要超过州警
Ooh,punch buggy yellow!
黄甲壳虫!(游戏)
Yellow-- that reminds me, I have to pee.
黄 唤起了我的尿意
Thank you!
谢谢!
- Great. - Oh,hey,Ted...
- 妙极 - 嘿 Ted
You can't have to go again. It's not humanly possible.
你不能再去尿了 再去就是非人类了
No,I was just going to say maybe we should listen to something.
不是 我刚要说我们能听点东西
Oh,that's a great idea. I think I have some Jerky Boys.
好主意 我有"捣蛋双宝"(喜剧)
Good-bye,Sparky.
再见 Sparky
It's an audio book about a boy and his dog.
是关于一个男孩和他的狗的有声书
It made Elisabeth Hasselbeck cry.
伊丽莎白哈瑟尔贝克都为之感动流泪 (脱口秀主持人)
Good-bye Sparky, by Nick Leotti.
再见 Sparky  Nick Leotti著
Read to you by Kenny Rogers.
朗读者 Kenny Roders
Chapter One: When I first saw Sparky, he reminded me of my favorite comb;
第一章 第一眼看见Sparky 我想起了我最爱的梳子
he was missing a lot of teeth, but I loved him anyway.
他掉了好多牙 但我依然爱他
Mother was fit to be tied every time he used her prized rhododendron to do his business.
每次他拿母亲喜欢的杜鹃花捣蛋时 母亲都生气极了
That reminds me, I have to pee.
唤起了我的尿意
"How many stars are on the flag?"
"国旗上有多少星星?"
50-- one for each state.
50 每个代表一个州
"What are the first ten amendments to the Constitution called?"
"宪法的前十个修正案叫啥?"
The Bill of Rights. Look,Barney,I know all this. I'm ready.
权利法案 听着 Barney 我全知道 我准备就绪了
Ready for the test maybe, but ready to be an American?
也许为考试做好了准备  但为做美国人呢?
Not on your sweet life.
可没那么轻巧
For you to be an American, we got to get the Canadian out of you.
为了你能把加拿大成分剔出体外 成为美国人
That's why I've created these questions.
我想出了这些问题
Question one: "Who is this?"
第一问"这是谁?"
Queen Elizabeth II.
女王伊丽莎白二世
No,the answer is Elton John.
错 答案是埃尔顿 约翰 (不拿英女皇当回事了)
Question two: "What the hell is this?"
第二问"这究竟是啥?"
Oh,curling. Um,it's a sport played...
冰球 是一种比赛
Wrong. The answer we were looking for was "I don't care,it's dumb."
错 我们要的答案是"管它呢 蠢蛋"
Let's go buy something that's bad for us and then sue the people who made it.
我们去买点烂货然后告生产商
That's America,Robin.
这才是美国 Robin
because Sparky loved chasing a ball, and it didn't much matter what kind.
因为Sparky喜欢追球玩 无论啥球
Tennis ball,baseball, Wiffle ball, golf ball,
网球 棒球 威浮球 高尔夫球
basketball, beach ball,gum ball, a grapefruit--
篮球 沙滩球 橡皮球 葡萄柚
which isn't actually a ball, but it's round like a ball--
其实它不是球 但它圆得象球
a football-- which isn't round, but it's still technically a ball--
橄榄球 不圆但还是球
Indian rubber ball...
印度橡胶球
This ends disk seven. The audio book continues on disk eight.
第七盘结束 请听第八盘
Disk eight.
第八盘
- Lacrosse ball,volleyball... - Oh,my God,Lily,please tell me you have to go pee!
- 曲棍球 排球 - 我的天 Lily 快说你要去尿尿
Yeah,I do.
确实要去
It was the worst trip ever, but then it got worse.
有史以来最烂的旅行 但没有最烂只有更烂
Well,don't worry,the next exit's the hotel. We can go there.
别担心 下一站是旅馆 我们去那尿
Hotel?
旅馆?
Crumpet Manor is listed in the American Registry of Historic Bed-and-Breakfasts.
Crumpet庄园是美国登记在册的提供早餐的老店
Our door is opened on Christmas day,1881.
我们是在1881年圣诞节开张的
And we have catered to couples ever since.
从那开始我们便为情侣提供服务
Well,I mean,single people can have fun here,too,right?
单身的人也能在这找到乐趣 对不?
Oh,I suppose I could arrange a little recreation.
我想我能安排些娱乐
Do you enjoy sitting on a bench?
你喜欢坐在长凳上不
And by the end of the night, Barney had turned Robin into a real American.
最后 Barney把Robin改造成了真正的美国人
I want to say-- Jefferson?
是Jefferson?
Correct. Archie Bunker's neighbor was George Jefferson.
对啦 Archie Bunker的邻居是 George Jefferson
Oh,boo-ya! I am nailing this.
哦也! 我成功啦
- God,I'm buzzing on America right now! - All right,hold your horses.
- 天哪 我变美国人啦! - 好啦 心急吃不了热豆腐
Now to prove that you are as American as apple pie and the childhood obesity it leads to--
为了证明你象导致儿童肥胖的 美国苹果派那样正宗
who is this?
这是谁?
That,Barney, is the American actor, beloved by millions,
Barney 这个是美国深受喜爱的
the "Hey,Vern" guy from the popular series of Ernest films.
Ernest电影系列里的说"嘿 Vern"的家伙
And his name...
名叫...
Jeff Foxworthy.
Jeff Foxworthy
Jeff Foxworthy? No,it's Jim Varney.
Jeff Foxworthy? 错 是Jim Varney
You're kidding me. You don't know that?
逗我玩呢吧 你不知道?
Uh,that's Jeff Foxworthy, dumbass. End of story.
是Jeff Foxworthy 蠢蛋 一切结束
Now shut your stupid face.
闭上你的臭嘴
Not only are you wrong,
你不仅答错
but you are belligerently sticking to your guns and insulting me in the process.
还一意孤行甚至辱骂我
Robin Scherbatsky-- you are an American.
Robin Scherbatsky 你是美国人了
Look who's back from the wishing well.
看呀 谁从许愿池边回来了
It didn't work, I'm still here.
不灵验 我还在这里嘛
Marshall,what are we doing? We should be on the road.
Marshall 我们搞啥? 我们本应在路上的
Look,Ted,we're not in college anymore,okay?
Ted 我们不再是大学生了
We don't have to drive all night.
我们没必要通宵开车
Besides,they have a spa. What kind of treatments do you offer?
还有 这里可以做水疗哦 你们这里提供什么水疗服务呢?
All our spa treatments are designed for couples.
这里所有的水疗服务都是为情侣而设的
Would you be interested in the two-person, cornmeal body scrub?
要不要来个双人 玉米精华磨砂膏疗程?
And then finally it happened.
然后 终于出现了
Marshall and Lily globbed into one big married glob.
Marshall和Lily融为一个爱情人团
We'd love a cornmeal body scrub!
玉米精华磨砂膏? 太棒了!
I got to dial back on the Tantrum.
我要再打电话订点Tantrum
Oh,yeah,I'm gonna be an American,y'all.
哦耶 姐现在是米国人了 哟嗷
Maybe I'll rob a liquor store. Maybe I won't. My choice.
老娘想打劫哪个酒水店就哪个 或者不打劫 我的地盘我做主
Learn English!
学点英语吧!
The Hoser Hut. I could duck in for a drink.
Hoser Hut酒吧 进去喝点小酒吧 (加拿大老乡吧)
No,no,that life's behind me. Forget it.
不 那已经是过去了 忘了它
Well,I could go in for just one beer.
呃 进去喝一杯啤酒而已
What's the harm in that? It's a free country.
无伤大雅? 这里可是自由的国度
?O Canada ?
"哦 加拿大" (加拿大国歌)
?Our home and native land...?
"我的祖国我的家"
Oh,God,I miss it.
天 我好想念啊
?True patriots love...?
"爱国者的爱..."
Hey,man.
嘿
Sorry about what I said before.
之前我说的话过分了 对不起
You want to go to the store and get some beer?
要不咱下去店里喝一杯吧?
Lily is asleep.
Lily睡着了
I suppose I could reschedule my pedicure.
我想我可以跟修脚师再约个时间
What the hell? But only light beer because we have a couples hike in the morning.
管他呢 不过只喝请啤就好了 明早咱小两口要去远足呢
Dude,why are we pulling on to the highway?
兄弟 为啥咱们会开上高速公路?
Ted,where exactly are we going to get this beer?
Ted 我们到底要去哪里喝酒?
Chicago.
芝加哥
What are you doing? We can't just leave Lily.
你在干嘛? 我们不能抛下Lily
When she wakes up, she's going to freak!
要是她醒来发现了 她会发疯的!
She'll have a back rub and a crumpet. She'll be fine.
我给她订了个背部按摩和烤面饼 她不会有事的
Relax. Have some fun.
放轻松 好好享受
I just abandoned my wife.
我抛下了我的妻子
How am I supposed to have fun?
你叫我怎么享受?
?And I would walk 500 miles ?
4分钟后 "让我一路向前500里 "
?And I would walk 500 more...?
"让我继续向前500里..."
Hey,you really think Lily's pissed?
嘿 你觉得Lily会不会真的生气?
If she's pissed,she's pissed.
生气就生气呗
When Barney finally tracked down your Aunt Robin, it wasn't a pretty sight.
Barney最后终于搜索到你们Robin阿姨 可那画面不太雅观
Good morning.
早哇
Barney? Oh,my God. What happened last night?
Barney? 天呐 昨晚发生了什么事?
You went Canadian.
你变得加拿大了
How Canadian?
有多加拿大?
This Canadian.
这么加拿大
That was supposed to be a dramatic view of the Toronto sky-- you're in Toronto.
这本来是戏剧性的景观 多伦多的天空 你在多伦多了
Oh,God.
天呐
Okay. It's coming back to me.
好 我慢慢想起来了
I,uh,I went into the Hoser Hut...
我 我去了Hoser Hut酒吧...
And I met this women's curling team.
遇到了一群女子冰壶队
We started drinking.
我们就喝起来了
And the next thing I know, they're inviting me to a Bryan Adams/Rich Little double bill in Toronto.
剩下的我只记得她们邀请我去多伦多 看Bryan Adams和Rich Little的连场表演 (均为加拿大艺人)
How did you find me,anyway?
话说回来 你怎么找到我的?
You called me, said you were never coming back.
你打给我 说你再也不回去了
So,I jumped on a plane, flew across the Atlantic...
所以我急忙跳上飞机 跨越大西洋...
- Canada isn't across the Atlantic. - You're talking nonsense.
- 来加拿大不需要穿过大西洋 - 孩子你都语无伦次了
Now,listen... You slipped up. It's fine.
听好了... 你失足了 但没关系
The test is in a few hours.
测试还有几小时就开始
Barney, I'm not taking the test.
Barney 我不参加那个测试了
God,you're still drunk.
苍天 你还醉着呢
Look,I-I appreciate your help,but...
我很感谢你这么帮我 但是...
who am I kidding? I'm Canadian. I always will be.
我在糊弄谁呢?  我是加拿大人 一直都会是
Now,that's ridiculous.
别说胡话了
We're gonna get some coffee in you,we'll sober you up,
咱们去喝点咖啡 让你清醒清醒
and get you back to New York for that test.
然后回纽约参加测试
But,before any of that, we're gonna do it on this bed 'cause... hotel room.
不过呢 在这之前 咱们先在床上测试一下 因为... 酒店房间哦
Okay,let's get some coffee.
好啦 咱们去喝咖啡
A little rubbery, room temperature... Kind of gross.
小有弹性 常温... 有点恶心
You're making me wonder if this pizza is worth the 22-hour drive.
你让我开始思考这比萨是否值得 我们花22小时开车过来
Just like old times!
就像以前那样啊!
I feel so young again except for the chest pains.
我感觉自己又回到年轻时候 除了我现在胸口痛
But the crust is so good. What is the secret to this crust?
这外皮太棒了 有什么秘诀呢?
It's no big secret. It's made of cornmeal.
没什么诀窍 这是用玉米粉做的
Cornmeal...
玉米粉...
We'd love a cornmeal body scrub!
玉米精华磨砂膏太棒了!
I can't believe you guys are closing.
我真不敢相信你们这里竟然关门大吉了
I can't believe we're still open. Gotcha!
我真不敢相信这里竟然还没关门大吉 抓到你了!
These are getting bigger.
真是越来越大了
It's like an entire country without a tailor.
看起来就像整个国家都没个好裁缝的样子
Yeah,give me two coffees.
两杯咖啡
3.50,please.
三块五 谢谢
Hey,what did you think of the game last night?
嘿 昨晚的比赛觉得怎样?
- What game? - The Leafs beat Edmonton.
- 什么比赛? - 多伦多枫叶队对埃德蒙顿呀
Beauchemin went five hole in OT.
Beauchemin打加时赛时进了五个
- Oh,I guess I missed it. - Oh,sorry. You're American. Here's your change.
- 我错过了那场 - 不好意思 你是美国人哦 找你的钱
I'm not American.
我不是美国人
American money? Didn't watch the Leafs game?
用美元? 不看枫叶队比赛?
No "please" or "thank you" for the coffee?
买咖啡不说"请"或者"谢谢"?
You sure don't seem like a Canadian.
我敢说你肯定不是个加拿大人哦
What's wrong?
有什么问题?
Other than the fact that this five-dollar bill they gave you is blue.
除了她们找给你的五块钱是蓝色之外
I'm not American, and apparently, I'm not Canadian either.
我不是美国人 显然也不是加拿大人
And there's kids playing hockey on the back.
还有 背面居然有几个孩子在玩冰球
It's like you want us to make fun of you.
这不是逼我们取笑你们吗
I don't want this anymore.
我不想再这样了
Dude,don't look at it. That's a rookie mistake.
伙计 别看直接吃就好啦 这是新手必犯的错误
We shouldn't have left Lily.
我们不该抛下Lily
Well,if you're so worried, why don't you give her a call?
你要这么担心的话 打电话给她呗?
I have. I left her,like,20 messages.
打过了 我给她 差不多留了20条口信
I said,"I'm sorry. Please forgive me. It's all Ted's fault!"
我说"对不起 请原谅我  这全是Ted的错!"
- What exactly is "Ted's fault"? - This! This whole thing!
- 什么叫 "Ted的错"? - 这些事! 这所有的事!
We were having a perfectly nice trip, and then you kidnapped me.
我们正开开心心的旅行  然后你绑架了我
You didn't even let me put on underwear!
甚至连内裤都没让我穿上!
We never used to put on underwear!
我们从来没有穿内裤的习惯!
That was the fun of a bro's trip to Gazzola's!
这才是这次兄弟旅行 去Gazzola's比萨店的乐趣所在啊!
We left everything, and everyone behind.
我们撇下所有事情 所有人
It was just you and me!
只有你和我!
But now it's like you've disappeared into Lily.
而现在 你就像迷失在Lily的温柔乡里
- That is not true. - It is true.
- 不是这样的 - 就是这样
You're not upset because you're worried she's mad.
只要担心着她会不会发怒你就不心烦
You're upset because you'd rather be with her, eating muffins than here with me, eating this delicious...
你宁愿跟她一起吃松饼 现在却心烦意乱  因为在跟我享受这美味的...
I think one of my mushrooms just crawled away.
我好像见到上面的蘑菇在蠕动
Well,you know what? That mushroom's not the only thing that's leaving.
知道吗? 不止那颗蘑菇要离开
Car keys,please.
车钥匙 谢谢
Look at this money!
看看这些硬币!
This one has a moose, this one has a beaver, and they all have Elton John on the back.
这个有只驼鹿 这个有只海狸 而背面都有艾尔顿约翰
When I moved to the States, I swore to myself, I wasn't going to change.
当我移居美国时  我向自己发誓 我不会改变
And yet,here I am,in the most Canadian place in the universe-- Tim Horton's--
而现在 我在全世界最有加拿大味的地方 Tim Horton's(加拿大快餐品牌)
around the corner from the Hockey Hall of Fame, and I don't belong.
正在冰球名人堂的拐角  而我却没有归属感了
It's like I don't have a country.
就好像我没有祖国那样
Okay,that's it.
够了
Attention,Canada!
听着 加拿大! (小Barney的地图攻击开始...)
I am Barney from America.
我是Barney 来自美国
And I'm here to fix your backward-ass country.
我是来拯救你们这狗屁倒灶的国家的
Number one: get real money.
第一 搞点真钱用吧
Don't know what board game this came from,but it's a "jhoke."
我不管这棋盘游戏是哪个国家发明的 但这是个"杯具"
Number two-- and this is the biggie--
第二 而这个很重要
Quit letting awesome chicks like Robin Scherbatsky get away because,guess what?
别再放过像Robin Scherbatsky 这种辣妹了 知道吗?
You don't want her?I'm planting my flag in her--
你们不想要她?  那我就在她身上插枝旗
if you know what I mean, which you probably don't--
希望你们懂我意思吧  当然很可能你们不懂
and getting her the hell out of here.
再把她带走
You may now return to being pointless.
继续你们无聊的人生吧
Ah,this coffee is excellent.
哦 这咖啡真不错
Hey,fellas.
嘿 兄弟
It's called a "tie""
这玩意儿叫"领带"
Sparky was my best friend,
Sparky是我的好朋友
but after I married Helen, old Spark started to feel a little left out.
但在我娶了Helen之后  老Spark开始有点低落
For so long, it had been just me and him,
这么长时间以来 一直都是我和它一起
but now he suddenly felt like Helen had taken his place.
而现在他觉得Helen突然间取代了他
What Sparky didn't realize was, even though I loved Helen, I still loved him,too.
Sparky不知道 虽然我爱Helen 但我还是爱它的
I had room in my heart for both of them.
我的心始终装着他们俩
But maybe I should have put aside some special ball-tossing time
可我应该腾出点时间陪它玩玩球
just for the two of us to make sure Sparky knew that he was a good boy.
给彼此 让Sparky知道我心里还是有它的
I wish now I had, 'cause old Sparky ran out in front of a Cadillac
我真希望我早点这么做  因为老Sparky被一部凯迪拉克撞倒
and got splattered like a watermelon in one of them Gallagher shows.
像Gallagher秀里的西瓜那样飞溅开
- I'm sorry,Ted! - I'm sorry! No,I'm sorry.
- 对不起 Ted! - 对不起 不 是我对不起你
I-I never should have been mad at you!
我不该生你气的!
No,I never should have brought Lily.
不 我不该带Lily来的
She pees all the time, even at the apartment.
她老是要尿尿 即使在家里也是
Still bros?
还是哥们不?
Best bros.
铁哥们
Hey,you want to crank some Van Halen just like old times?
嘿 想要像以前那样听范·海伦乐队吗?
Hells,yeah!
当然!
Or listen to the Sparky book again?
或者再听一遍这Sparky的书?
- Listen to the Sparky book again. - Okay. Let's listen to it again.
- 听Sparky的书吧 - 好 再来一遍
Man,those Canadian doctors bandaged me up, reset my jaw,
老天 那些加拿大医生把我包扎起来 装好下巴
put my shoulder back in its socket, and they didn't even bill me. Idiots.
再帮我把肩膀移好位  居然没给我开账单 一群白痴嘛 (加拿大医疗免费滴)
All right, I guess they're not idiots.
好啦 他们没那么白痴
The coffee was extraordinary.
那里的咖啡真的很棒
I guess Canada's not so bad.
我想加拿大没我想象中那么差
They play their cards right, maybe they can even become a state someday.
要是他们干得好  说不定真的能成为一个州呢
Barney,I've thought about this.
Barney 我想过了
When you stood up and told off those people, I thought,"Yeah, America's cool"" .
那时你站起来说教那些人 我就在想 "美国也挺酷嘛"
And then when those guys pounded the stuffing out of you,
后来那些人猛锤你的时候
I thought,"Yeah,Canada's pretty cool,too."
我就想"加拿大也挺酷的"
In fact,after you passed out, I-I may have taken a few pokes myself.
事实上 你晕过去之后 我也偷袭了你几下
So,I've decided, dual citizenship.
所以我决定了 做双重公民
I'm going to be American and Canadian.
我要同时做美国人和加拿大人
- Wait,you can do that? - Yeah,dummy.
- 等等 这样可以? - 当然 小傻瓜
Instead of being a woman with no country, I'm going to be a woman with two.
比起做一个无国之人  我宁愿成为两国公民
I see.
我懂了(我看到了)
You understand?
你能理解?
No,I can see out of my left eye again.
不 我是说我能用左眼看东西了
- Hey,baby? Baby? - Yeah?
- 嘿 宝贝? 宝贝? - 怎么了?
I'm so sorry that we left you.
我们抛弃了你 对不起
Did you go somewhere,sweetie?
你去了哪里 亲爱的?
Yes,kids,it turns out Crumpet Manor had pampered Lily into a nearly comatose state of relaxation.
没错 孩子 看来Crumpet庄园 让Lily陷入一种昏昏欲睡的放松状态
She didn't even notice we were gone.
她甚至没意识到我们走了
Yeah...
爽...
So,I had a great time,too.
我也很开心呀
That's good. And I'm so sorry you didn't get any pizza.
那就好 对不起没给你带比萨
Oh,that's okay.
没事啦
And if she didn't mean it then, she certainly meant it 19 minutes later.
要是现在她言不由衷的话  19分钟后就是真心实意的了
God,my stomach! Damn you,Gazzola's!
我的肚子! 去死吧 Gazzola's比萨店!
It's like a hot ball of lead!
就好像胃里有个火烫的球!
Baby,cut it out of me. Cut it out!
宝贝 快割掉它 割掉它!
That was a wild trip,huh,Ted?
好一个旅行啊 是吧? Ted
I know. It was kind of crazy.
就是 太疯狂了
But how great is it to drink some Tantrum again?
不过能再喝到Tantrum多棒
You know who had fun,was Lily.
知道谁最开心吗 是Lily
Lily drank,like,four cans of the stuff. Right,Lil?
Lily好像喝了四罐这东西 是吧? Lil
- Where's Lily? - Tantrum!
- Lily呢? - Tantrum!
I have to pee.
我要尿尿